Joseph Stramaglia

Design Leader, Creative and Analytical



Executive Summary

Excellent leader in game design and development that can take your organization to new heights. I've been described by teammates as an **absolute operator** and as a **force multiplier**. I strive to *always* be leveling up.

- Proficient at the highest level down to the smallest details
- Experienced in every facet of game design
- Decorated experience in game economy design and systems balancing
- Works smart, not hard by increasing efficiency and targeting outcomes vs output

Core (Com	petencies

Problem Solving, Attention to Detail, Communication, Cross Disciplinary Team Work, Analysis, Emotional Intelligence, Leadership and Strategic Thinking

Research and Development, Technologically Adaptive, Systems Design, Economy Design, Monetization, User Experience, Playtesting and Prototyping, Live Operations, Sales and Events, Content Design, Narrative Design, Data Driven Design, CCGs, 4X Strategy, Hero Battlers, RPGs, Idle Games, FPS, Action

Software and Processes

Unity, Unreal, Roblox, Version Control, Visual Studio, Excel, Google Sheets, PowerPoint Presentations, Jira, Asana, Trello, Confluence, Notion, PHP, C#, Javascript, Adobe Creative Suite, Maya, Miro, Design Tools, Deployment, Product Leadership, Game Production, Quality Assurance, Live Operations (SaaS), Interface Design, Feature Specifications, Living Documentation

Experience	
-	

Supersocial, Inc. *Lead Game Designer*

Chicago, IL (Remote) 02/2021 - 03/2022

Started out as lead design on our flagship title, eventually branched out to a role fulfilling similar duties across our entire portfolio as well as developing pitches and prototypes for unannounced projects in the Roblox and web3 space.

- Mentored a group of young professionals in game design and professional development
- Worked closely with C-level executives as an advocate for design
- Built out a set of design tools and processes that allowed for non-technical simultaneous implementation of content through Google Sheets and GitHub
- Title credits: Ghostopia, Land of Merchants, Ballista, Pirates vs Ninjas, Rogue Mythos, an unannounced brand experience, and an unannounced web3 project.

Palo Alto, CA 05/2020 - 02/2021

Acquired Machine Zone, after the transition my contributions expanded to developing feature designs, strategies, and events that were implemented into the entire portfolio.

- Worked closely with leadership to foster creative and scalable design solutions
- Created detailed design specifications with considerations for the different teams and their unique complex economies, as well as business impact
- Title credits: Game of War, Mobile Strike, World War Rising, Final Fantasy XV: A New Empire, and unannounced titles

Machine Zone (MZ) Game Designer

Palo Alto, CA 02/2019 - 05/2020

Quickly ramped up on their design processes and began training new designers.

- Collaborated with live operations to create monetization opportunities and was principal in one of our most successful sales and events in the title
- Built design tools and processes that improved pipeline and increased design flexibility while decreasing implementation time
- Title credits: World War Rising

Kongregate (Synapse Games)Project Lead

Chicago, IL 08/2014 - 02/2019

Product Owner and Project Manager for our flagship mobile title Tyrant Unleashed. Technical design and pre-production for the entire portfolio of games in tandem.

- Proactively monitored KPIs, prioritized resources, maintained product roadmap and software development life cycle, built out tools and processes used across all games
- Creatively lead design aspects from game balancing, economy, systems and feature development, live operations events, content, narrative, mission design
- Personally pitched, designed, and created the most successful single IAP in the entire company's portfolio that was not topped for years
- Title credits: TMNT: Mutant Madness, Animation Throwdown, Spellstone, Tyrant Unleashed, Global Assault, Castaway Cove, Unreleased 4X/Hero Battler

Other Relevant Experience

Milyli, Inc.

Quality Assurance Engineer

Chicago, IL 03/2013 - 08/2014

- Built test automation, plans, test driven design, and developed ASP.Net Applications in a Model Viewer Controller architecture
- Last 4 Months: I functioned as a Client facing Full Stack Web Developer.

Warner Games (NetherRealm Studios)

Quality Assurance Analyst

Chicago, IL 01/2013 - 03/2013

• 3 Month Contract to bring Injustice Gods Among Us to Gold

• Had the highest number of reported critical or higher bugs in the organization

Neutron Star Games Studio

Chicago, IL

Co-Founder

01/2014 - 10/2017

DePaul Game Envision

Chicago, IL

Project Lead, Design Director

06/2011 - 11/2011

Cainee LLC

Chicago, IL

Game Design Consultant

2012

Freelance

Remote

Web Developer

2008 - 2013

DePaul University

Chicago, IL

Game Lab Technology Manager

01/2010 - 11/2012

Organizations and Volunteering

Game Developers Conference

Chicago, IL

Conference Associate

2014 - Present

BitBash

Chicago, IL

Volunteer Captain

2014 - Present

DePaul University

Chicago, IL

Senior Capstone Advisor

2013 - 2016

DePaul Fundamental Research in Academic Gaming

Chicago, IL

President and Board Member

02/2021 - 03/2022

Education

DePaul University

Chicago, IL

B.S. Computer Games Development, Game Design and Production

2012

Referrals available upon request